Register of the Pasternak Family Papers, 1877-2012
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1921-1990 (Box 30-34)
  - Adelson, Stella
    - Correspondence addressed to Josephine, Lydia and other members of the Pasternak family
      - 1921
        - September (Box-folder 30: 24)
        - October (Box-folder 30: 25)
        - November (Box-folder 30: 26)
        - December (Box-folder 30: 27)
      - 1922
        - January (Box-folder 31: 1)
        - February (Box-folder 31: 2)
        - March (Box-folder 31: 3)
        - April (Box-folder 31: 4)
        - May (Box-folder 31: 5)
        - June-July (Box-folder 31: 6)
        - August (Box-folder 31: 7)
        - September (Box-folder 31: 8)
        - October (Box-folder 31: 9)
        - November-December (Box-folder 31: 10)
      - 1923
        - January-February (Box-folder 31: 11)
        - March-April (Box-folder 31: 12)
        - May-June (Box-folder 31: 13)
        - August-September (Box-folder 31: 14)
        - October-November (Box-folder 31: 15)
        - December (Box-folder 31: 16)
      - 1924
        - January-April (Box-folder 31: 17)
        - May-July (Box-folder 31: 18)
        - August-September (Box-folder 32: 1)
        - October-November (Box-folder 32: 2)
        - December (Box-folder 32: 3)
      - 1925
        - January-February (Box-folder 32: 4)
        - March-April (Box-folder 32: 5)
        - May-June (Box-folder 32: 6)
        - July-August (Box-folder 32: 7)
        - September-October (Box-folder 32: 8)
        - November-December (Box-folder 32: 9)
      - 1926
        - General
          - January-February (Box-folder 32: 10)
          - March-May (Box-folder 32: 11)
          - June-August (Box-folder 32: 12)
          - September-October (Box-folder 32: 13)
          - November-December (Box-folder 32: 14)
        - Pasternak, Ernst (Box-folder 32: 15)
      - 1927
        - January-May (Box-folder 32: 16)
        - June-December (Box-folder 32: 17)
      - 1928 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - 1929
        - January-July (Box-folder 33: 2)
        - August-December (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - 1930
        - January-June (Box-folder 33: 4)
        - August-December (Box-folder 33: 5)
      - 1931 (Box-folder 33: 6)
      - 1932
        - January-June (Box-folder 33: 7)
        - July-December (Box-folder 33: 8)
      - 1933 (Box-folder 33: 9)
      - 1934 (Box-folder 33: 10)
      - 1935
        - January-May (Box-folder 33: 11)
        - June-August (Box-folder 33: 12)
        - September-October (Box-folder 33: 13)
      - 1936 (Box-folder 33: 14)
      - 1937 (Box-folder 33: 15)
      - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 33: 16)
      - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 33: 17)
      - 1966-1968 (Box-folder 33: 18)
      - 1971-1978 (Box-folder 33: 19)
    - Writings (Box-folder 33: 20)
  - Bobrov, Sergei (Box 34)
    - General. "Sergei Bobrov i ego volshebnyi dvurog," Detskaia Literatura, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Writings
      - "Opyt izucheniia vol'nogo stikha pushkinskikh 'Pesen' zapadnykh slavian'," Teoriia veroiatnostei i ee primeneniia, Akademiia nauk S.S.S.R., Moscow, 1964 (Box-folder 34: 2)
      - Excerpts from Mal'chik re Leonid Pasternak, Typescript, 1966 (Box-folder 34: 3)
      - Russkaia Literatura, Akademiia nauk S.S.S.R., Leningrad, 1966 (Box-folder 34: 4)
      - "Stikhi raznykh let," Prostor, 1970 (Box-folder 34: 5)
      - Evgenii Delakrua: Zhivopisets, Sovetskii Pisatel', Moscow, 1971 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Dobrovein, M., "Vecher Aisedory Duncan," Typescript with inscription by Aleksandr Pasternak. See also PHOTOGRAPHS, Isadora Duncan, 1974 (Box-folder 34: 7)
  - Lobanov-Rostovsky, Nikita. See also JOSEPHINE PASTERNAK FILE, Correspondence. Printed matter re Russian stage design, collected by Nikita Lobanov-Rostovsky, 1969-1993 (Box-folder 34: 8)
  - Navrozov, Andrei. See also JOSEPHINE PASTERNAK FILE, Correspondence
    - Clippings, 1960 January 6 (Box-folder 34: 9)
    - Review of Andrei Navrozov's poetry by Josephine Pasternak, Typescript, 1987 (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - Writings
      - General, Typescript and printed, 1986 (Box-folder 34: 11)
      - Transport of Elements, Typescript corrected manuscript, 1985 (Box-folder 34: 12)
  - Pasternak, Charles. Correspondence with Judah L. Magnes Museum, 1983 (Box-folder 34: 13)
  - Pasternak, Evgenii, "Portrety Gordona Krega," Moskovskii Nabliudatel', Printed copy, 1991 (Box-folder 34: 14)
  - Pasternak, Zinaida, "Vospominaniia," Neva, Printed copy, 1990 (Box-folder 34: 15)
  - Ramsay, Helen. Correspondence
    - General, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 34: 16)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 34: 17)
    - Hirschl & Adler Galleries, Inc., 1982-1983 (Box-folder 34: 18)
    - Institute of Modern Russian Culture, Includes correspondence with John Bowlt, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 34: 19)
    - Judah L. Magnes Memorial Museum, See also correspondence of Helen Ramsay with Ruth Rischen, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 34: 20)
    - Navrozov, Andrei, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 34: 21)
    - Ramsay, Michael, 1983 (Box-folder 34: 22)
    - Rischen, Ruth, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 34: 23)
  - Schnack, Ingeborg
    - Correspondence, 1961-1990 (Box-folder 34: 24)
    - Writings, "Zwei Briefe an Max Lehrs zur russischen Kunst," Typescript, undated (Box-folder 34: 25)
  - Skriabin, Aleksandr, concert program, 1909 (Box-folder 34: 26)
  - Slater, Michael. Correspondence with Ruth Rischen, 1983 (Box-folder 34: 27)
  - Society for Cultural Relations with the USSR, 1990 (Box-folder 34: 28)
- RARE BOOK FILE, 1919-1943 (Box 35-36)
  Printed copies of Russian prose and poetry published in Berlin and Paris in the 1920s, arranged alphabetically by name of author.
  - General (Box 35-36)
    - Novyi Mir, nos. 7-8, Moscow, 1943
    - Russkii Sovremennik, no., 2, 1924
    - Versty, no. 1, Paris, 1926
  - Akhmatova, Anna
    - U samogo moria, "Akonost," St. Petersburg, 1921
    - Anno Domini, Petropolis-Alkonost, Berlin, 1923
  - Andreev, Leonid, S. O. S., Helsingfors, 1919
  - Babel', Isaac, Korol', Izdatel'stvo "Ocharovannyi Strannik," Paris, 1926
  - Bal'mont, Konstantin, Sonety solntsa, meda i luny. Pesnia mirov, Izdatel'stvo S. Efron, Berlin, undated
  - Belyi, Andrei, Stikhotvoreniia, Izdatel'stvo Z. I. Grzhebina, Berlin, 1923
  - Bunin, Ivan, Poslednee svidanie, Idanie T-va "N. P. Karbasnikova," Paris, 1927
  - Esenin, Sergei, Moi put', Izdatel'stvo "Ocharovannyi Strannik," Paris, 1926
  - Shaliapin, F. I., Maska i dusha: Moi sorok let na teatrakh, izd.-tvo "Sovremennyia Zapiski," Paris, 1932
  - Tolstoy, Lev, Ne mogu molchat': O smertnykh kazniakh, J. Ladyschnikow Verlag G.m.b.H., Berlin, undated
  - TSvetaeva, Anastasiia, Dym dym i dym, L. L. Levenson, Moscow, Frontispiece includes holograph dedication of author to Boris Pasternak and other notations, 1916
  - TSvetaeva, Marina
    - Tsar'-Devitsa: Poema-Skazka, Epokha, Berlin, 1922
    - Posle Rossii: 1922-1925, Paris, 1928
- RESTRICTED SERIES, 1921-1960 (Box 37)
  Original material that may be viewed under supervision only, consisting of correspondence of Boris Pasternak with Leonid, Rosalia, Josephine, and Fedor Pasternak and with Lydia Pasternak-Slater (use copies in Box 12) and of letters from Marina TSvetaeva to Leonid Pasternak (use copies in Box 2). Also includes original material in the hand of Boris Pasternak, consisting of writings and letters to Marina K. Baranovich, a poem by Rainer Maria Rilke copied by Boris Pasternak, Boris Pasternak's typewritten translation of Faust (with handwritten annotations), and a handwritten note by Boris Pasternak on Doktor Zhivago (use copies in Box 39).
  - Original correspondence of Boris Pasternak with Leonid, Rosalia, Josephine, and Fedor Pasternak and with Lydia Pasternak-Slater, (use copies in Box 12), 1921-1945 (Box-folder 37: 1-16)
  - Original letters from Marina TSvetaeva to Leonid Pasternak, 1922-1928 (use copies in Box 2) (Box-folder 37: 17)
  - Original material in the hand of Boris Pasternak, 1948-1960 (use copies in Box 39), consisting of writings and letters to Marina K. Baranovich as well as of a poem by Rainer Maria Rilke copied by Boris Pasternak (Box-folder 37: 18)
  - Original typewritten translation of Faust by Boris Pasternak (with handwritten annotations), (use copies in Box 39), undated (Box-folder 37: 19)
  - Original handwritten note on Doktor Zhivago by Boris Pasternak, (use copies in Box 39), undated (Box-folder 37: 20)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1880-1989 (Box 38)
  21 prints and 1 postcard depicting members of the Pasternak family and their friends; and 2 glass plates, 1 of a letter from Iliia Repin to Leonid Pasternak and 1 of a clipping re Leonid Pasternak exhibit at Kunsthandlung Victor Hartberg.
  - 4 prints depicting Josephine Pasternak with works by Leonid Pasternak, Oxford, 1980 (Box-folder 38: A)
  - 2 prints depicting Josephine Pasternak and her husband Fedor Pasternak (Box-folder 38: B)
  - 2 prints depicting Evgenii and Elena Pasternak and Bill and Helen Ramsay at the Leonid Pasternak exhibit in the Tsentral'nyi Dom Khudozhnika, Moscow, 1989 (Box-folder 38: C)
  - 3 prints depicting a street sign in honor of Leonid Pasternak in Israel, undated (Box-folder 38: D)
  - 1 print of Leonid Pasternak's portrait of Gossia Gurdus-Stiebel, Includes note by Josephine Pasternak, 1981 (Box-folder 38: E)
  - 1 print of Oxford landscape by Leonid Pasternak, 1940s. See also JOSEPHINE PASTERNAK FILE, Correspondence with British Medical Journal (Box-folder 38: F)
  - 1 print depicting C. Lyautey, Odessa, Inscribed for Leonid Pasternak, 1880 (Box-folder 38: G)
  - 1 print depicting Isadora Duncan. Signed (Box-folder 38: H)
  - 1 print depicting Kurt Huber and 3 prints depicting Alexander Schmorell (Box-folder 38: I)
  - 4 miscellany prints and 1 postcard (Box-folder 38: J)
  - 1 glass plate of letter from Iliia Repin to Leonid Pasternak., undated (Box-folder 38: K)
  - 1 glass plate of clipping re: Leonid Pasternak., undated (Box-folder 38: L)
- USE COPIES, 1948-1960 (Box 39)
  Photocopies of original material in the hand of Boris Pasternak, consisting of writings and letters to Marina K. Baranovich, a poem by Rainer Maria Rilke copied by Boris Pasternak, Boris Pasternak's typewritten translation of Faust (with handwritten annotations), and a handwritten note by Boris Pasternak on Doktor Zhivago (originals in RESTRICTED SERIES).
  - Photocopies of original material in the hand of Boris Pasternak, consisting of writings and letters to Marina K. Baranovich,. Includes a poem by Rainer Maria Rilke copied by Boris Pasternak, 1948-1960 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Photocopy of typewritten translation of Faust by Boris Pasternak (with handwritten annotations), undated (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Photocopy of handwritten note on Doktor Zhivago by Boris Pasternak, undated (Box-folder 39: 3)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1986-1993
  Videotape cassette of Josephine Pasternak's interview for "Wortwechsel" and phonotape cassette of Evgenii Pasternak's speech at Josephine Pasternak's funeral.
  - Phonotape cassette, Evgenii Pasternak speech at the funeral of Josephine Pasternak, 1993
  - Videotape cassette, Josephine Pasternak interview "Wortwechsel,", 1986
- INCREMENTS, 1924-2007 (Box 39-59)
  Includes letters and postcards to Josephine Pasternak from her father Leonid Pasternak, her cousin Ol'ga Freidenberg, and other relatives; writings by Boris Pasternak, including original typewritten manuscript (with handwritten annotations) and use copy of an early version of Doktor Zhivago; printed copy of Indefinability, by Josephine Pasternak; printed matter, including articles by Ol'ga Freidenberg, some signed by her; background material for Lazar Fleishman's book, Boris Pasternaks Lehrjahre, consisting mostly of photocopies of Boris Pasternak's student notes published in the book; letters from Aleksandr I. Solzhenitsyn, Mariia Voloshina, A. TSvetaeva, and Lev Kopelev; poems by A. Kochetkov, Sofiia Parnok, and Vera Zviagintseva; books by others, including by Goethe and Shakespeare, translated by Boris Pasternak and inscribed by him to Marina K. Baranovich, and by Aleksandr I. Solzhenitsyn, inscribed by him to Anastasiia A. Polivanova; Lydia Pasternak sound recordings
- PASTERNAK TRUST ARCHIVES, 1877-2012; 118.0 boxes
  Correspondence, diaries, memoirs, other writings, biographical data, printed matter, drawings, photographs, and other audiovisual material relating to Russian art and literature, culture in the Soviet Union, and Russian émigré life. Includes papers of Leonid Pasternak; his son, the poet and novelist Boris Pasternak; his daughters, Lydia and Josephine Pasternak; and other family members.
  - LYDIA PASTERNAK SLATER FILE, 1917-1989; 70.0 boxes
    - Biographical material, 1917-1988; 1.0 box (Box-folder 62: 1-16; 124: 7)
      Arrangement Statement
      Arranged alphabetically by physical form, then chronologically
      - Address lists, undated (Box-folder 62: 1)
      - Award certificates, 1978 (Box 169, Box-folder 62: 2)
      - Birthday book, undated (Box-folder 62: 3)
      - Business cards, undated (Box-folder 62: 4)
      - Education records, 1917-1933 (Box-folder 62: 5, Box 169)
        Includes high school diploma, Moscow University transcript, and Berlin University diploma.
      - Employment records, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 62: 6)
      - Cultural events information, 1961-1988 (Box-folder 62: 7-8)
        - Art exhibitions
        - Literary events
        - Concerts and recitals
      - Invitations, 1959-1987 (Box-folder 62: 9)
      - Life events announcements, 1935-1988 (Box-folder 62: 10)
      - Notebook, undated (Box-folder 62: 11)
      - Passports, 1951-1981 (Box-folder 62: 12)
      - Poetry reading programs, 1960-1986 and undated (Box 169, Box-folder 62: 13)
        Includes letters from Christopher Maslanka.,
      - Travel and transportation documents, 1960-1988 (Box-folder 62: 14)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box-folder 124: 7)
    - Correspondence, 1918-1989 (Box 63-110)
      Correspondence was divided into General and Family correspondence, each arranged alphabetically by last name, then chronologically by year.
      - General, 1918-1989 and undated (Box 65-110)
        Includes letters from friends, business letters, and Lydia's draft letters.
        - General, 1918-1989 and undated
          - Condolence letters on the death of Boris Pasternak, 1960 (Box-folder 63: 1-2)
          - Draft letters, 1943-1987 and undated (Box-folder 63: 3-5)
          - Greeting cards, 1918-1989 and undated (Box-folder 63: 6-9; 64: 1-9)
            - 1918-1953 (Box-folder 63: 6)
            - 1954-1958 (Box-folder 63: 7)
            - 1959-1963 (Box-folder 63: 8)
            - 1964-1968 (Box-folder 63: 9)
            - 1969-1972 (Box-folder 64: 1)
            - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 64: 2)
            - 1975 (Box-folder 64: 3)
            - 1976-1980 (Box-folder 64: 4)
            - 1981-1983 (Box-folder 64: 5)
            - 1984-1989 (Box-folder 64: 6)
            - undated (Box-folder 64: 7-9)
          - National Committee for Rescue from Nazi Terror file, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 65: 1)
            Includes Rescue for Perishing pamphlet by Eleanor Rathbone, letters from the United Jewish Relief Appeal, and Lydia’s draft letters to various institutions and individuals.
          - Telegrams, 1930-1984 and undated (Box-folder 65: 2-4)
          - Third party letters, 1964-1981 (Box-folder 65: 5)
        - A. Neimanis Buchvertrieb GMBN, 1964-1988 (Box-folder 65: 6)
        - Abbey of Gethsemane, 1961 (Box-folder 65: 6)
        - Abelin, I., 1934
        - Acumen Magazine, 1987
        - Adam International Review, 1968
        - Adam, Gabriel (Gaby), 1974-1982
        - Adelson, Abram, letters to Lydia, 1920s -1976 and undated (Box-folder 65: 7-10; 66: 1-10)
          - circa 1920s (Box-folder 65: 7)
          - 1921-1922 (Box-folder 65: 8)
          - 1923-1924 (Box-folder 65: 9)
          - 1925-1926 (Box-folder 65: 10)
          - 1927-1928 (Box-folder 66: 1)
          - 1929-1932 (Box-folder 66: 2)
          - 1933-1935 (Box-folder 66: 3)
          - 1936-1937, circa 1930 (Box-folder 66: 4)
          - 1956-1959 (Box-folder 66: 5)
          - 1961-1964 (Box-folder 66: 6)
          - 1965 (Box-folder 66: 7)
          - 1966-1967 (Box-folder 66: 8)
          - 1968-1969, circa 1960s (Box-folder 66: 9)
          - 1970-1976 (Box-folder 66: 10)
        - Adelson, Stella, letters to Lydia, 1920-1984 and undated (Box-folder 67: 1-11)
          - 1920-1927 (Box-folder 67: 1)
          - 1928-1929 (Box-folder 67: 2)
          - 1930-1934 (Box-folder 67: 3)
          - 1935-1938, 1945, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 67: 4)
          - 1960-1962 (Box-folder 67: 5)
          - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 67: 6)
          - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 66: 7)
          - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 67: 8)
          - 1970-1978 (Box-folder 67: 9)
          - 1979 (Box-folder 67: 10)
          - 1980-1984 (Box-folder 67: 11)
        - Adelson, Abram and Stella, letters to Lydia, 1955-1977 (Box-folder 68: 1-10; 69: 1-4)
          - 1955-1961 (Box-folder 68: 1)
          - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 68: 2)
          - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 68: 3)
          - 1966 (Box-folder 68: 4)
          - 1967 (Box-folder 68: 5)
          - 1968 (Box-folder 68: 6)
          - 1969 (Box-folder 68: 7)
          - 1970 (Box-folder 68: 8)
          - 1971 (Box-folder 68: 9)
          - 1972 (Box-folder 68: 10)
          - 1973 (Box-folder 69: 1)
          - 1974 (Box-folder 69: 2)
          - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 69: 3)
          - 1977 and undated (Box-folder 69: 4)
        - Adel'son, Abram and Stella, letters from Lydia, 1926-1978 and undated (Box-folder 69: 5-11)
          - 1926, 1935, 1959 (Box-folder 69: 5)
          - 1961-1964 (Box-folder 69: 6)
          - 1965 (Box-folder 69: 7)
          - 1966-1968 (Box-folder 69: 8)
          - 1969, circa 1960s (Box-folder 69: 9)
          - 1970-1972 (Box-folder 69: 10)
          - 1976-1978 and undated (Box-folder 69: 11)
        - Adey, Lionel, 1961 (Box-folder 69: 12)
        - Adler, Marni, 1968
        - Admiralty, Director of Navy Account, 1954
        - Aeby, Alphonse, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 70: 1)
        - Aherns(?), Mayner, 1973, 1975 (Box-folder 70: 2)
        - Aill, Michael, undated
        - Akademiia Nauk SSSR, Institut mirovoi literatury im. A.M. Gor’kogo, 1970
        - Alfred Stiles and Sons Ltd., 1967
        - Allan, James, 1961
        - Albanis, Donis, 1969
        - Aldus Books Ltd., 1964-1965
        - Alekseenko, N, 1968
        - Alfus, Angel, 1968
        - All Souls College, 1961
        - Allen, Anula, 1966-1974 and undated
        - Allen-Harbick, Manette, 1966
        - Allied Records Ltd., 1959
        - Allison and Busby Ltd, publishers, 1970
        - Alma Mater Philippina, 1963-1971; bulk 1963
        - Almedingen, Edith, 1958-1988
        - Amal, D. Litt, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 3)
        - Amato, Mario, 1960
        - American Biographical Institute, Inc., 1987
        - Amsden, Jean, 1962
        - Amsgericht Tiergarten, 1974
        - Andersen, Danielle, 1969-1980 and undated
        - Andreyev, Nikolai, 1974
        - Andreev (Carlisle), Olga, 1971
        - Andreeva, Ekaterina, 1980
        - Andrew, Jacques, Bulk, 1959; 1953-1960 and undated; bulk 1959 (Box-folder 70: 4)
          Includes his writings.
        - Angelus, Novus, 1970 (Box-folder 70: 5)
        - Anglo-Soviet Medical Council, 1943
        - Annely Juda Fine Art, 1970
        - Anning, N. J., 1966
        - Antenen, Achilles, 1988
        - Anthology of Hungarian Poetry in English Translation, 1967-1972
        - Antonova, Elizabeth, 1961-1977
        - Anvil Press Poetry (see also: Peter Jay), 1970
        - Appelfeld, A., 1968
        - Apt, Lisa, 1983
        - AQUILLA magazine, 1976 (Box-folder 70: 6)
        - Archer Gallery, 1972
        - Archiv für Kunst und Geschichte, 1962
        - Archives Centrales Albert Schweitzer, 1975
        - Ardis Publisher, 1973-1978
        - Aren(?), Irina, 1981-1985
        - Arkay, J. C., 1963
        - Armstrong, Robert, 1961-1965, 1971
        - Arnod, John, 1971 (Box-folder 70: 7)
        - Art and Sound, 1964
        - Art Auction, 1965-1987
        - Art Needlework Industries Ltd. (A.N.I.), 1975
        - Arts Council of Great Britain, 1958-1961
        - Ashmolean Museum, 1957-1985 (Box-folder 70: 8)
        - Ashmore, Basil, 1959-1961 and undated (Box-folder 70: 9)
        - Associated Press, 1968
        - Association of Teachers of Russian, 1971
        - Astbury, Anthony, 1970-1986 and undated
        - Astrov, Gennadii, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 71: 1)
        - Aucouturier, Michel, 1972-1977
        - Avon Books, 1966
        - Ayton, Leo (Venture Films), circa 1967
        - Babaev, E., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 71: 2)
        - Babler, Otto, 1968
        - Badenoch, John, 1977-1979, 1983
        - Baker, Eileen, 1985-1986
        - Balfin, J., 1966, 1983
        - Balfour, Gwen, 1954-1988 and undated (Box-folder 71: 3-7)
          - 1954, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 71: 3)
          - 1971-1979 (Box-folder 71: 4)
          - 1980-1984 (Box-folder 71: 5)
          - 1985 (Box-folder 71: 6)
          - 1986-1988 and undated (Box-folder 71: 7)
        - Balfour, Gwen and Roger, 1962-1988 (Box-folder 71: 8-11)
          - 1954, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 71: 8)
          - 1971-1982 (Box-folder 71: 9)
          - 1983-1986 (Box-folder 71: 10)
          - 1987-1988 and undated (Box-folder 71: 11)
        - Balfour, Muriel, 1959-1967 (Box-folder 72: 1-2)
          - 1959-1962 (Box-folder 72: 1)
          - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 72: 2)
        - Balges, Theo, undated (Box-folder 72: 3)
        - Baranova (Baranoff), N., 1958-1959
        - Barber, Elizabeth, 1981
        - Bardas, Marianne, 1972-1984
        - Barder, Christopher, 1981
        - Bargie, Joe and Rosie, undated
        - Barkovsky, K., undated
        - Barnardo’s, 1981
        - Barnes and Noble, Inc., 1965-1966
        - Barnes, Christopher, 1964-1986 and undated (Box-folder 72: 4-5)
          - 1962-1975 (Box-folder 72: 4)
          - 1971-1986 and undated (Box-folder 72: 5)
        - Barri and Jenkins Ltd., 1971 (Box-folder 72: 6)
        - Bartascheff, A., 1964
        - Bartels, Adolf Georg, 1974
        - Barton, S., 1967
        - Barwise, Lily, 1945-1983
        - Basil Blackwell Publisher, 1971
        - Bate, Donald, 1977
        - Bates, Diana, 1963-1964
        - Bayley, John, 1966-1967
        - Becqué, Louis, undated (Box-folder 72: 7)
        - Beer, François-Joachim, 1961
        - Beikine, Colette, 1988
        - Beirne, John, 1986-1987
        - Behrman, Rena, 1970-1971
        - Beilby, John, 1982
        - Beliakova, Tamara, 1974
        - Belize, S., 1962
        - Bell’s Travel, 1945
        - Belboula Ali-Instituteur, 1960
        - Belling, Adelaida, 1976-1977
        - Ben Uri Art Gallery, 1962
        - Bentley, Joel, 1974-1975
        - Bernard Stone Bookstore, 1964
        - Berg, J. H. van der, 1977, 1986
        - Berger, Elaine Friede, 1960
        - Berlin, Isaiah, 1956
        - Bessendorf, Mikhail, 1980
        - Besançon, Alain, 1978
        - Betjemen, John, 1975
        - Bezalel National Museum, 1959
        - Biblotèque Nationale, Paris (Sophie Laffitte), 1960, 1978
        - Bickley, Olga, 1958
        - Bindman, David, 1969
        - Bintos(?), Eva, 1970
        - Birch, Leo, 1976-1979
        - Birmingham Post, undated
        - Bisewska, Anna, 1977
        - Bishop, Barbara, 1974-1989 (Box-folder 72: 8-9)
          - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 72: 8)
          - 1976-1989 (Box-folder 72: 9)
        - Blackwell, F. M., 1963-1964, 1976 (Box-folder 72: 10)
        - Blackwell, Joan, 1976
        - Bland, Deidre, 1973
        - Blantke(?), Hermann, 1962
        - Blanshard, Francis, 1963
        - Blaschko, undated
        - Blechschmidt, Christie (?), 1972
        - Block, Alfred, 1941
        - Blume, A., 1962-1963
        - Blyk, Natalia, undated
        - Boden, Roger, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 73: 1)